totalrl.com 2016-05-14

# Privacy Policy | Latest News. Match Results. What the fans are predicting. Everything you need to know about what's happening in Rugby League today. Take a look here!

Please take a moment to read this privacy policy carefully as it provides information about League Publications Ltd’s (“LPL”) information, collection, use and handling practices. If you have any questions whatsoever, please do not hesitate to contact us using the information in the section below entitled “Contact Information”.

LPL takes it commitment to privacy seriously and, therefore, has adopted this privacy policy to let you know:

How we collect information and what types of information we collect.

How we use the information we collect and for what purposes.

When and to whom information we collect may be disclosed.

How we safeguard and protect Personal Information (defined below) you provide.

The choices that are available to you regarding our collection and use of Personal Information.

How you may access, review and change Personal Information you provide.

For the purposes of this privacy policy, “Personal Information” is personally identifiable information about an individual person such as a person’s name, physical address, email address and telephone number, as more particularly described under applicable privacy laws.

1\. Policy Scope: This privacy policy applies to all of LPL’s businesses, affiliates, and subsidiaries, including, but not limited to our websites, and covers the use and disclosure of information that LPL may collect any time you interact with us eg: when you use our websites, when you call our customer service department, or when you purchase any of our products and services.

OUR WEBSITES ARE INTENDED TO BE ACCESSED AND USED ONLY FROM THE UNITED KINGDOM. If you are accessing and using our websites from outside the UK, please note the information that you provide will be transferred to the UK or other countries which may not provide the same level of legal data protection as the country from which you access our websites. By using our websites and submitting information to us, you consent to such transfers and the processing of information by us as described in this privacy policy and you authorise this practice.

LPL’s websites may provide links to websites owned or operated by third parties or otherwise direct you to websites owned or operated by third parties (“Linked Websites”). Your use of Linked Websites will be governed by terms of use, privacy policies and other additional terms, notices and policies set forth or referenced in those Linked Websites. This privacy policy does not reflect the information collection, use and disclosure practices of the Linked Websites or the operators or owners of Linked Websites. To understand how a Linked Website and the owners or operators of a Linked Website will collect, use, store and otherwise make available information you should review the Linked Website’s privacy policy.

2\. Updates and Changes to Policies: LPL may change this privacy policy from time to time by posting updated versions of the privacy policy here. If we make changes to the privacy policy we will post a notice on our website of such change. However, as this notice will only remain up for seven days after the changes are posted, we suggest that you review this privacy policy from time to time. Please note that information we collect will be treated in accordance with the privacy policy in effect at the time the information is collected.

3\. Our Information Collection, Use and Disclosure Practices: Personal Information Provided Voluntarily by the User. You may be asked to provide or otherwise voluntarily provide Personal Information when you participate in various services and offerings available through our websites, when you contact us via phone, mail, or otherwise, and when you participate in our competitions and related promotions. The Personal Information we may ask you to provide includes, but is not limited to, the following categories of information: your name, mailing address, email address, telephone number, year of birth, and gender, information concerning your hobbies, interests and occupation, financial information (for billing purposes), and opinions, responses and other material you post to our websites.

Though you may access and use portions of our websites without providing any Personal Information, in order to take advantage of the full capabilities of our websites and to obtain access to, and use of, many of the features of our websites, you must provide certain Personal Information. For example, in order to register for an account through our websites and to request information about of products and services you must provide certain Personal Information.

Certain functionalities available through our websites may require you to provide information about third parties. This information may include a third party’s name, address, phone number, fax number, email address, and other similar information. If you provide Personal Information to us, including Personal Information regarding individuals other than yourself, you represent and warrant that (i)  
you have the authority to provide such Personal Information and to grant LPL the right to use such Personal Information consistent with this privacy policy, (ii) you have provided such Personal Information voluntarily, and (iii) you consent to the use of such Personal Information in the manner envisioned by this privacy policy.

We use Personal Information you provide to us for our business purposes, such as (i) to allow you to access your Website account, (ii) to confirm your identity, (iii) for marketing our products and services to you and to customise this advertising and marketing information (iv) to contact you regarding your Website account and to keep records regarding your Website account, (v) to carry-out promotions, including but not limited to contests surveys and related promotions that you have entered; (vi) to provide the services and products you request and to respond to your other requests and inquiries, (vii) to enhance our service offerings; and (viii) to adjust our websites to your personal preferences. Except as specifically provided in the following paragraph, we will not sell or rent or otherwise share the Personal Information you provide to us with third parties.

We may share Personal Information you provide to us with certain third parties that perform services on our behalf. Those third parties may host our websites; provide certain features or functionality; print or send mailings or emails (including marketing materials); provide the services you request, authorise and process your payments; provide customer service; analyse data; or otherwise assist us with the operation of our business. Those third parties are not authorised to use or disclose Personal Information for any purpose other than to perform the services designated by LPL. We may also provide the Personal Information you provide to us to a third party if we are required by law or litigation so to disclose such Personal Information. For example, we may be required to disclose Personal Information to respond to a court order or other legal process. Finally, the Personal Information you provide to us may be transferred as an asset in connection with a merger or sale involving all or part of LPL or as part of a corporate reorganisation, stock sale or other change of control.

Information Collected from Other Sources.

We may obtain information about you from other sources, such as companies that update and verify email and physical addresses, for the purpose of updating and enhancing our files.

Automatically Collected Information.

When you access or use our websites we automatically collect and store the following types of non- personally identifiable information (information that is compiled in anonymous and aggregate form and is not used to locate, contact, or identify you specifically), where available, in additional to the Personal Information you provide voluntarily: information from server logs found on your browser, click-through statistics, your IP address, the type of application (e.g. web browser) you are using to access our websites, the type of operating system you are using, the name of the domain and host from which you access the Internet, the date and time you access parts of the websites, and the Internet address of the site from which you linked directly to our websites. We use Google Analytics to learn about where our visitors come from and how they interact with the Website. Google and its wholly owned subsidiaries may retain and use, subject to the terms of the Google Privacy Policy (located at http://www.google.com/privacy.html, or such other URL as Google may provide from time to time), anonymous traffic data collected in our use of Google Analytics.

We will use the information we automatically collect through your access and use of our websites to determine how our websites are accessed and used. For example, this information will allow us (i) to determine which pages are the most popular with users, (ii) determine if our websites are working properly, and (iii) to improve the user-experience on our websites. We do not use automatically collected information to identify a particular user.

We may aggregate and use certain non-personally identifiable information for research or marketing purposes and may share, sell and rent or trade that information and statistical data derived from such information with our marketing partners, advertisers, or other third parties for research or marketing purposes.

4\. User Communities on our Websites.

As stated above, we collect information about you through your interactions with us. Our websites include community areas (e.g., forums, bulletin boards and chat rooms) in which you may participate after establishing an associated account. Although your participation in these communities is governed by this privacy policy, there are certain important characteristics of these communities that you should always keep in mind.

We use registration information and other information users provide as they interact within the communities to: authenticate users; provide communications from us to users regarding the community; and administer the community (including, but not limited to, managing the technical requirements of the site and monitoring submissions and posts for offensive content after posting and removing such content in our sole discretion).

Please note that information (including your name, email address, address, or phone number) you provide in a posting on community or any bulletin board is available (even after you stop participating in the community) to any other individual who has access to that same community and may be used by another individual in a manner unintended by you, including as a target for unsolicited communications. You should therefore treat any information provided by you in the content of a submission or post to a community as public information. For this reason, we urge you to act cautiously in providing any such information in your submissions or posts, as we are not liable for any use or misuse by an individual user of the information you provide in a submission or post.

Upon termination of a community, Personal Information we collected through the community will continue to be treated in accordance with this privacy policy.

5\. Cookies and Related Technology “Cookies” are small text files that a website sends to a user’s hard drive through the browser for data storage. We use Cookies to store information about your visits to our websites and to enhance your experience when visiting our websites. For example, we use Cookies to, among other things, identify previous visitors to our websites, identify a user as he/she moves through our websites, track user visits and account set-ups, determine what set-ups are most frequently requested, and save your password so you do not have to provide it each time you visit our websites. Storing information about your visits to our websites will allow us to, on occasion, customise account pages for you.  
By themselves, Cookies do not tell us your e-mail address or other personally identifiable information. We do not use Cookies to collect, track, or store personally identifiable information.  
Our cookies will never be used to track your activity on any third party websites or to send spam.  
You can configure your browser to accept all Cookies, reject all Cookies, or notify you when a Cookie is received. (Each browser is different, so check the Help menu of your browser to learn how to change your Cookie preferences). You may reject, delete or otherwise disable Cookies at any time.  
However, by deleting, rejecting or otherwise disabling Cookies, you may inhibit your user experience on our websites and you may not be able to take full advantage of all offerings on our websites. For example, if you disable or reject cookies you will not be to purchase products or services. In addition, if you disable or disallow Cookies, some multimedia images and graphics may not display properly, you may not be able to view customisable features, and/or you may have more difficulty navigating through our websites.

Some of our email communications to you may include a “click-through URL” linked to a particular page on one of our websites. By clicking on one of these URLs, you will automatically enter our website. Our systems track this information to gauge the effectiveness of our email communications and your level of interest in particular areas. You may avoid having this information collected by avoiding clicking on URL links in our email communications. Please note, that we will NEVER send you an email with an imbedded link that asks for your password or any financial or account information; passwords are for your protection. If you EVER receive such an email, please contact us immediately using the information in the Section 9 below entitled “Contact Us”.

We use pixel tags to identify what pages of our website are visited most frequently and to evaluate the effectiveness of the search functions on our website.

6\. Notice for Parents: Our websites are general audience sites that are not targeted for use by children. LPL does not intend to collect Personal Information from individuals under the age of thirteen (13) on or through our websites. If you are the parent or guardian of a child under the age of 13 who has provided Personal Information to us, please inform us as provided below in Section 9 (“Contact LPL”) below, and we will delete that Personal Information.

7\. Security: We employ reasonable measures, including administrative, technical, and physical measures, to protect Personal Information from unauthorised access, loss, alteration, use or disclosure. Our websites are capable of using Secure Sockets layer 128-bit encryption and we will use at least such level of encryption in the transmission of Personal Information from our websites to our servers.  
End-to-end (i.e. from your browser to our servers) Secure Socket layer 128-bit encryption may be available in some instances only if you provide technology capable of such encryption (e.g. you use a browser to interact with our websites that are capable of Secure Sockets layer 128-bit encryption). In addition, we use reasonable technical and physical measures to limit the disclosure of Personal Information consistent with this privacy policy. However, Personal Information can never be 100% secure: information may be transmitted over networks without appropriate security measures and may be accessed, deleted, altered, used or disclosed by unauthorised persons. You can help us to protect the Personal Information you provide to us by (i) not sharing your password or other account information with others, (ii) using a secure web browser, and (iii) frequently changing your password.

8\. Managing Information: You may update the information you provide by accessing your account and following the instructions set forth therein. You may opt-out of receiving certain types of communications from us. However, you will not be able to opt-out of receiving other types of communications, such as service announcements and administrative messages, as these types of communications are necessary if you have an account with us. You may opt-out of receiving Optional Communications by following the instructions set forth in those communications or by accessing your account and following the instructions set forth therein. If you have any questions regarding your ability to opt-out of receiving certain types of communications please contact us using our contact information set forth below in Section 8 (“Contact LPL”). Please note that removal of Personal Information from our database or “opting-out” will not stop marketing or advertising content that is ready to be mailed or is queued for transmission to you prior to the time when we can implement your request.

We reserve the right to retain any Personal Information reasonably necessary to appropriately document our business activities and for archival and record retention purposes. We will store Personal Information for as long as reasonably necessary for the purposes described in this privacy policy. You may find out more details regarding this privacy policy by contacting us as provided below.

9\. Contact Us: If you have questions regarding our websites, our services, the privacy policy or your privacy while accessing or using our websites, you can [click here to use the contact form on this website](http://www.totalrl.com/league-publications-ltd/ "League Publications Ltd") or write to us by post at League Publications Ltd, Wellington House, Briggate, Brighouse, West Yorkshire, HD6 1DN, United Kingdom, or you may call us at +44 (0) 1484 401895.
